{
    "id": "825b65717e8a4293a79364cfb3803170",
    "title": "Gerund Or Infinitive",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I hate the idea ……………….. old.",
            "description": "The noun idea is followed by a preposition + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to get",
                "of getting",
                "of get"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The thought ……………… never bothered him.",
            "description": "The noun thought is followed by a preposition + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to fail",
                "of failing",
                "to failing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is very clever ……………….. problems.",
            "description": "The adjective clever is followed by the preposition at + ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "in solving",
                "to solve",
                "at solving"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Have you got anything ………………. flies?",
            "description": "After something and anything, we use for + ing form to explain the purpose of an object.",
            "answers": [
                "to kill",
                "for killing",
                "for to kill"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You can’t eat meat without …………….. an animal.",
            "description": "After a preposition, we use an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "to kill",
                "killing",
                "of killing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You must always check the oil before ……………… the vehicle.",
            "description": "After a preposition, we use an ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "to start",
                "starting"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I am not used to ………………. in a major city.",
            "description": "When to is a preposition, it is followed by an ing form. A common expression in which this happens is ‘be used to’.",
            "answers": [
                "live",
                "living",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you object to ……………. on weekends?",
            "description": "In the expression object to, ‘to’ is a preposition. We use ing forms after prepositions.",
            "answers": [
                "work",
                "working",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Be careful when you talk to him. He is inclined to ……………… his temper.",
            "description": "The verb inclined is followed by a to-infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "lose",
                "losing",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We are waiting for the guests …………….",
            "description": "The verb wait is followed by for + object + infinitive.",
            "answers": [
                "to arrive",
                "to arriving",
                "arriving"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We regret …………… passengers that the flight to Amsterdam has been cancelled.",
            "description": "Regret is followed by an infinitive in announcements of bad news.",
            "answers": [
                "to inform",
                "informing",
                "to informing"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I regret ……………… out of college. It was a big blunder.",
            "description": "Regret is followed by an ing form to refer back to the past.",
            "answers": [
                "to drop",
                "to dropping",
                "dropping"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}